madison-reed.com 2018-11-16

# Madison Reed – Privacy Policy

Last Updated: June 8, 2018

* * *

This Privacy Policy explains how information is collected, used and disclosed by Madison Reed with respect to your access and use of our services through our websites and applications, and when you visit one of our “Color Bar” hair color salon locations. This Privacy Policy doesn't apply to any third-party websites, services or applications that can be accessed through our services.

Any information that is collected is subject to the Privacy Policy in effect at the time such information is collected. We may, however, modify and revise our Privacy Policy from time-to-time. If we make any material changes to this policy, we will notify you of such changes by posting them on our website, and we will indicate when such changes will become effective. The new privacy policy will apply to all current and past users of our website, mobile app, or other services, and will replace any inconsistencies in prior policies. By continuing to access or use our services after those changes become effective, you are agreeing to be bound by the revised policy. 

## Information You Provide

We will collect the personal information (like your name, email address, phone number) you provide when you register for an account and additional information (like billing information) you provide in connection with the purchase of products and/or services through our website. We also collect personal information from you when you make a booking online through our website, on the phone or in-person for services at one of our Color Bar salons. We may also maintain a record of your product purchases made on our website or at one of our Color Bar salons.

If you create an account using your login from a supported social networking site (like Facebook), we will access and collect the personal information about you that the social networking site allows to be shared (which is based your privacy settings, but may include your name, gender, and profile picture), in order to create your account for you and better personalize your customer experience. We may collect the contact information of your friends (if you choose to connect your friends, contacts and address book information with your account) so that you can contact these people when you use our services or to refer a friend to our services.

We collect personal information you provide from other sources, including Madison Reed websites, mobile applications, when you call or email us, communicate with us through social media, or when you participate in events or other promotions. This may include, among other things, any photographs or reviews shared with us through social media, the Madison Reed website, or mobile app. We also may obtain information about you from our parent, affiliate or subsidiary companies, business partners and other third party services and organizations to supplement information provided by you. This supplemental information allows us to verify information that you have provided to Madison Reed and to enhance our ability to provide you with information about our business, products, and services.

Note regarding children:  We do not knowingly collect personal information from children. If we learn that we have collected personal information of a child under 13, we will take steps to delete such information from our files as soon as possible.

Note regarding international users:  Your information will be transferred to and maintained on computers located in the United States (or any other country where we operate) and processed there – by providing us with your information, you are accepting and agreeing to that transfer

## Information We Collect

We automatically collect certain information when you use our services, like the Internet Protocol (IP) address (if using a browser) or a device identifier (if using a mobile device), operating system, the browser type, referring website information, and your location (if you enable this feature). You can enable or disable location services when you use our services at anytime, through your browser or mobile device settings. We collect this information through our app or by using "cookies” (a small data file that your browser places on your computer that helps us better understand how you interact with and use our services). Most Internet browsers automatically accept cookies and you can instruct your browser, by editing its options, to stop accepting some types of cookies or to prompt you before accepting a cookie from the websites you visit. For the cookies that your browser may not be able to reject, you may be able to opt out of these technologies by visiting the NAI’s opt out page at [ http://www.networkadvertising.org.](http://www.networkadvertising.org/)

## How We Use the Information We Collect

We use the information we collect to provide our services (or the information you request), to process and complete any transactions, to respond to your inquiries, to personalize and improve our services and your experiences when you use our services, to monitor and analyze usage and trends of our services, to send you messages about the operation and use of our services, to market our products and services or those of our business partners to you via email and postal mail or via phone calls, and for the purpose for which the information was collected. For example, when you provide your email address during registration, we may sign you up for our email newsletter.

## Opt Out of Communications

If you wish to unsubscribe from marketing email, please click here to notify us. If you wish to unsubscribe from postal mail communications, please email us at [optout@madison-reed.com](mailto:optout@madison-reed.com) with your full name mailing address, and email address and tell us which information you do not want to receive. We will take steps to remove you from our communications. Note that you will continue to receive transaction-related emails regarding products or services you have requested. We may also send you certain non-promotional communications regarding Madison Reed and our services and you will not be able to opt out of those communications (e.g., communications regarding updates to our Terms of Service or this Privacy Policy).

## Information We Share With Others

We may share your information as described in this Privacy Policy (e.g., with our third-party service providers; to comply with legal obligations; to protect and defend our rights and property) or with your permission.

We may share information about you in anonymous and/or aggregated form with third parties for industry analysis, demographic profiling, research, marketing, analysis and other similar purposes.

Your information may be accessed and used by our service providers who are working with us in connection with the operation of our services (these service providers may have access to your information but only to the extent necessary to perform services on our behalf and are obligated not to disclose that information or use it for any other purposes).

We may share your information (including personal information) with third parties for their advertising and marketing purposes. These third parties may contact you in order to provide you with information about their products and services that you may find useful. If you prefer that we do not share your information with these third parties, you may contact us at [optout@madison-reed.com](mailto:optout@madison-reed.com) with your request as stated above under “Opt-Out of Communications".

We may share information about you if we are (or if we believe we are) required by law or legal process (such as a subpoena, warrant or court order), if we have to respond to a lawful request from legal authorities to disclose such information, or if we need to enforce or apply this Privacy Policy, our Terms or our other policies.

We may transfer and/or provide information about our users in connection with an acquisition, sale of company assets, or other situation where user information would be transferred as one of our business assets.

## Advertising and Analytics Services Provided by Others

We may enable third parties to collect usage analytics about our services. These third parties may place their own cookies on your device to collect traffic and activity data in order to deliver us relevant metrics and information. We may share anonymous or aggregated information about our users with them to help improve our services. The collection of this data by these third parties is subject to their own privacy policy.

We use Google Analytics to learn more about our users' and customers' experience on our website. This includes collecting some demographic information about our customers and users. We will only use this information to build a better product for our customers and users. This information is collected in aggregate and will never be associated with identifying information. For more information about Google Analytics, please visit www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/. You can opt out of Google’s collection and processing of data generated by your use of the Services by going to [ http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout.](http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout)

From time to time, we may establish a relationship with select business partners, where we rent, exchange, share and/or cross reference information, including contact information about you that will help these partners to contact you regarding products and services that may be of interest to you. To serve you better, we may combine (i) information we receive from you through online cookies and other technologies with other de-identified data (such as hashed, non-readable email or postal addresses), (ii) publicly available information, and (iii) information we receive from cross-references with these partners, to help us enhance and personalize your shopping experience. To learn more about targeted advertising, these providers, or how you may opt out, please visit the DAA’s consumer choice page at [ http://www.aboutads.info/choices.](http://www.aboutads.info/choices)

We allow third party companies to serve ads and/or collect certain anonymous information (e.g., click stream information, browser type, time, etc.) when you visit our website, which allow us and our partners to provide advertisements about products and services likely to be of interest to you. These companies typically use a cookie or 3rd party web beacon to collect this information. Our systems do not recognize "Do Not Track" signals, but most of these companies who utilize these cookies or beacons on our website enable you to opt out of this behavioral advertising. To opt out of advertising that uses technologies such as cookies to serve you with personalized ads, click here.

We may share your personally-identifiable information, including your name, address, email address, as well as a record of any transactions you conduct on our website or offline with us with a third-party advertising partner and its service providers in order to deliver to you banner advertisements and other advertising tailored to your interests when you visit certain websites. Our advertising partner will make the data we provide it anonymous. To learn more about the use of this information or to make choices about receiving personalized advertising provided by third parties, please visit the Network Advertising Initiative at <http://www.networkadvertising.org/>. 

## How to Access Your Information

If you have an account, you can access and modify the information you provided us through your account. If you cancel your account, then your account will become deactivated and you will not be able to access our services through your account. We may retain an archived copy of your information as required by law or for other legitimate record keeping purposes.

## Security Measures We Take To Protect Your Information

We employ physical and electronic measures designed to protect your information from unauthorized access, however, despite these efforts, no security measures are perfect or impenetrable and no method of data transmission can be guaranteed against any interception or other type of misuse. In the event that your personal information is compromised as a result of a breach of security, we will promptly notify you if your personal information has been compromised, as required by applicable law.

## Links to Other Services and Websites

Our services may contain links to other services and websites operated by third parties. Any information you provide to those services and websites is provided directly to the owner of that service or website and is subject to their own terms, data gathering practices and privacy policy. Our Privacy Policy does not apply to these services and websites and we are not responsible for the privacy and security practices of those services and websites.

Please contact us if you have any questions about our Privacy Policy.
